Now More Than Ever!
The Player is a mystery, drama, thriller film directed by Robert Altman.
A Hollywood studio executive is being sent death threats by a
writer whose script he rejected - but which one?
Griffin Mill, played by Tim Robbins.
June Gudmundsdottir, played by Greta Scacchi.
Walter Stuckel, played by Fred Ward.
Detective Avery, played by Whoopi Goldberg.
Larry Levy, played by Peter Gallagher.
Joel Levison, played by Brion James.
The Player is a 1992 American satirical black comedy mystery film directed by
Robert Altman and written by Michael Tolkin, based on his 1988 novel.
The film stars Tim Robbins, Greta Scacchi, Fred Ward, Whoopi Goldberg, Peter Gallagher, Brion James and Cynthia Stevenson, and is the
story of a Hollywood film studio executive who kills an aspiring screenwriter he believes is sending him death threats.
The Player has many film references and Hollywood in-jokes, with 65
celebrities making cameo appearances in the film.
Altman once stated that the film "is a very mild satire," offending no one.
The film received three nominations at the 65th Academy Awards: Best
Director, Best Adapted Screenplay and Best Editing.
The film also won two Golden Globes, Best Motion Picture – Comedy or
Musical and Best Actor – Comedy or Musical for Robbins.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
homicide, movie business, blackmail, screenwriter.
The tone is intense and lighthearted and emotional.